In this video, we will learn about another advanced visualization tool: the
word cloud. So what is a word cloud? A word cloud is simply a depiction of the
importance of different words in the body of text. A word cloud works in a
simple way; the more a specific word appears in a source of textual data the
bigger and bolder it appears in the world cloud. So given some text data on
recruitment, for example, we generate a cloud of words like this. This cloud is
telling us that words such as recruitment, talent, candidates, and so on,
are the words that really stand out in these text documents. And assuming that
we didn't know anything about the content of these documents, a word cloud
can be very useful to assign a topic to some unknown textual data. Unfortunately,
just like waffle charts, Matplotlib does not have a built-in function to generate
word clouds. However, luckily a Python library for cloud word generation that
was created by Andreas Mueller is publicly available. So, in the lab session
we will learn how to use Mueller's word cloud generator and we will also create
interesting word clouds superimposed on different background images. So make sure
to complete this modules lab session. And with this, we conclude our video on word
clouds. I'll see you in the next video.